





Mob: 07907 617 855 Email: <u>paul.hoang.uk@gmail.com</u> Website: fluffymango.co.uk

N.I: upon request

Github: github.com/General-Meow

Looking for: Contract work

Rate: Dependent on role (£450 - £800)

Availability: May

Location: London (no travel)

Nationality: British

Paul Hoang

A self-motivated and proactive man, who has over 13 years experience in the IT industry, 11 of which are in Java development. Currently looking for **CONTRACT** roles in **LONDON** around the DevOps space. This role could even be a hybrid role where I could leverage my development experience in Java. Willing to learn on the job and push for excellent results while pushing and mentoring other team members.

Key Technical Skills

Main Focus -	Java 6/7/8 (6 certified) - Spring - Spring Integration - Spring Boot - Spring Batch - REST -
Back End	GraphQL - Java Spark (Web framework not big data) - J2EE - Servlets - SQL - Hybris
Front End	HTML - JSP - CSS - LessCSS - JavaScript - Typescript - Angular2 - Jade (PUG) - jQuery -
	jQuery Mobile – Spring MVC
Servers	Tomcat - Jetty - Apache Web server – Nginx
Databases	Oracle - MySQL - Hibernate - Schema Design
Methodologies	Agile - Object Oriented Programming - Test Driven Design - Domain Driven Design -
	Microservices – Cloud - Scrum
DevOps	AWS (EC2, S3, VPC, Route 53, Security groups etc) - Ansible - Docker - docker-compose -
	Continuous Integration / Deployment (CI/CD) – Jenkins (Pipelines)
Other	Requirements Capturing – Windows 7/8/10 - Linux – Mac OS - Netbeans – Intellij Idea -
	Eclipse - Apache Ant – Maven – Gradle - Mercurial – Git - Subversion - JUnit - Mockito-
	Technical Design Documentation – UML – Mentoring - E-Commerce

Employment

April 2019 – Present

Fluffy Mango

DevOps Engineer

After working with the NHS for 2 years and gaining some experience of DevOps, I decided to take some time out to widen my skillset in this domain. So I spent time learning Terraform with AWS. I've gotten to a point where I'm comfortable using it as I've gotten to a stage where I'm creating VPC's, Security groups, EC2 Instances all from code.

I've also gotten fluffy mango's website up and running on AWS using static websites feature on S3 and DNS on Route 53. The plan is to use AWS as a platform to expand my experience with kubernetes and have a fully cloud native app running there with a full CI/CD pipeline

Feb 2017 - March 2019

NHS (HEE)

Senior Fullstack Developer

Employed as a senior fullstack developer doing mostly backend development in Java 8. Writing REST based microservices using technologies such as Spring boot (Web, Batch, Data), Hibernate, Flyway, SQL, Docker, Ansible. On the frontend the stack included angular 2 (ng2), angular 1, LessCss.

The team I joined is a medium sized agile team, that had quite a custom workflow. Whereby tasks/stories were not estimated and process was more like ScrumBan.

My latter responsibilities have moved more into a managing role as a large part of the team have now moved on. I have recently been trying to fix team dynamics and process by introducing more structure and moving the team towards Scrum. Training and mentoring junior developers has taken more time as well as architecting the solution and fixing technical debt. Other things include working more closer with DevOps as well as working on DevOps

related stories, scheduling/running interviews for new team members and running scrum ceremonies.

The project I worked on was the trainee management system that was being deployed nationwide. It was heavily microservices based and ran along side the existing legacy system that was being replaced. This meant that we had master/slave/migration challenges which involved many custom ETL's that ran nightly. Other parts of the system were spun up at a rapid pace using Jhipster which allowed us to create many services within weeks.

September 2016 – Jan 2017

CrownPeak

Senior Fullstack Developer

Employed as a senior fullstack developer doing mostly frontend development on the in house CMS application. The technology stack included angular 2 (ng2), angular 1,LessCss, Node npm, Bower, Jade (Pug), Visual Studio, Windows 10.

The team I joined is a highly self organised agile team, running grooming sessions, retrospectives, iteration kick off meetings and end of train demos.

November 2015 – Sept 2016

e2v

Senior Hybris Developer

Onsite as a hybris developer contractor. e2y is a young agile company, developing ground breaking e-commerce solutions focusing on high quality code and processes.

While there I designed and developed software solutions for a high end fashion marketplace retailer on the hybris platform. They were using hybris 5.7 with an on going process to upgrade to hybris 6

August 2015 - Oct 2015

rightmove.co.uk

Senior Fullstack Developer

Rightmove is the number one property listing website, with millions of new properties listed. As a senior developer, I worked on a number of the backend tools used by both the business and the estate agents. My time is split between supporting the old applications as well as developing new features for the current system.

May 2010 – August 2015

Neoworks (Salmon)

Senior Hybris Developer

Ecommerce consultancy that implements Hybris (SAP) systems. I've worked on a number of projects while at neoworks and some of these are for companies such as: Ted Baker, BBC, Asics, Toys R Us (both desktop and mobile sites), Nikon, The Toyshop, DHL, Target, iStone, HQHair, Urooms and the neoworks website.

Tech stack used: Java, Spring, Spring MVC, Spring Integration, Spring Roo, Hibernate, Hybris, servlets, mercurial, html, JSP, CSS

Certifications

- Sun Certified Java Programmer 6 (SCJP 6)
- Hybris Core Developer
- Hybris Commerce
- AWS Certified Developer Associate 2017
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate 2017
- Professional Scrum Master (PSM)

Education

University of Westminster 2002-2005

BSc Software Engineering Degree 2:2 (for full listing of modules available upon request)

A levels and GCSE are available upon request

References

Available upon request